this exercise requires us to
use the select method to extract all odd
numbers from this array
we're going to place these odd numbers
into a new array
so we know we want to invoke the select
method on our array
each element of this array will be
passed to the block
we'll name our block parameter number
now let's hop into irb to demonstrate
how we can determine if a number is odd
when we use the modulo operator to
determine the remainder of
dividing a number by two
we expect that the remainder will be
zero only if that number is even
so this code i've just written on line
one we expect to return
zero because the remainder of dividing 4
an even number by 2 is 0.
and that's what we see now what happens
when we do the same with an
odd number let's choose 5 since
5 cannot be evenly divided by two
we see a remainder of one
so in order to determine whether a
number is an even number
we can compare that return value to zero
in this case we want to extract only the
odd numbers
because we expect that this operation
will not return 0 for odd numbers
we've written our code on line 4
accordingly
the comparison on line 4 will return
true for odd numbers
because they cannot be evenly divided by
and false for even numbers therefore the
return value for our block will be
truthy
only for odd numbers let's store the
returned new array in a variable
and on line seven i'll output that new
array
and there we see our new array
containing only the odd numbers
another way that we could determine
whether each of these numbers is odd
is to invoke the integer odd method
this method returns a boolean either
true or false
if the number is odd it returns true
if it's even it returns false
so we'll run our code one more time and
see these same values in our new array
and we do
you